to create a mail merge in Word for mark
there are some slight differences than
doing this in Word for Windows as you
can see all of the tabs are the same and
thus the mailing tab is there which I
can click on which will bring up the
tools required to create the mail merge
I also have on the screen the letter
that I downloaded from the vision tool
in website to demonstrate with the first
thing you need to do when you're using
word for mark to create a mail merge is
you have to do each of the steps
individually there's no mail merge
wizard there's no facility to insert
address block and greeting line each
field has to be entered individually so
the first thing to do is right click on
start mail merge you would select the
type of document that you want to create
the mail merge with so for this instance
it's a letter
so quite happy with that so select
letter I then need to select the
recipients so selecting the recipients
is basically linking the letter with the
data source and the names and addresses
of the people who I'm sending that a to
have been inserted into an Excel
spreadsheet so if I click on that and I
want to use an existing list so I then
need to navigate to where I have saved
the list of names and addresses I know
it is in sum or e mail merge addresses
so I could click open and again in this
file I downloaded from the vision alone
website I will get a message up asking
me if I'm sure I want to open it as it
may oppose a security risk but I am
secure in the knowledge that this
document is not corrupt in any way I
select yes and then it will open up a
new dialog box asking which sheet I want
to check the data from and I know ochite
one and select book here so nothing's
actually happened but it has linked the
letter to the mail merge address fields
I now need to start adding the merge
fields so if I click on the insert merge
field button I need to insert the first
name and then in a row space and then
the cernium and then press ENTER then
address lane 1 enter address link 2 and
the town and the county and armed the
post court so that is knowing that all
of the individual fields required for
the name and address
I also wish to add a greeting link so I
will press ENTER twice to take me two
lanes down and I will type in the word
deer and then press the spacebar and go
back to the insert merge fields and
select first name and again press the
spacebar and then
sirmium so now let us insert a degree
ting Lane I'm just going to backspace
just to bring the letter on the body of
the letter up to beneath the greeting
Lane I will have a quick look and I'm
happy with that
I can then preview the results of the
merge so at the moment is just suing the
merge fields so if I click on preview
results it will automatically link the
data source with the letter sort of
start pulling through the names and
addresses so as you can see the first
name and addresses come up there William
Brown and the greeting link yeah William
Brown I can then navigate across to the
preview for the next record and it will
show me Jennifer Green has been entered
Fred white and Julie black so at this
point I can do any make any changes I'd
do something different or I can actually
you know remove a recipient off edit the
recipients felt the recipients there I'm
happy with that I would then go to the
finish and merge click on that and I can
either edit individual documents so I
could make changes to a specific
document maybe that I'm often a better
offer to one person on another or print
documents and if I click on print
documents I can then decide which way I
want it printed how many copies I want
and so on